Guide to the Arnold Lerner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arnold Lerner papers
1960-1968
MS 1679
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, and printed material relating to the Ulysses S. Grant Scholarship Foundation. The foundation, a privately run, non-profit organization, was founded in the early 1950s by Eugene Van Voorhis, a Yale freshman. Its goal was to provide tutoring by Yale student volunteers to African-American males in New Haven public schools in preparation for admission to private schools. These papers were compiled by Lerner during his tenure as a guidance counselor in the New Haven public school system.
Lerner, Arnold
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of acquisition unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, and printed material relating to the Ulysses S. Grant Scholarship Foundation. The foundation, a privately run, non-profit organization, was founded in the early 1950s by Eugene Van Voorhis, a Yale freshman. Its goal was to provide tutoring by Yale student volunteers to African-American males in New Haven public schools in preparation for admission to private schools. These papers were compiled by Lerner during his tenure as a guidance counselor in the New Haven public school system.
African American students; African Americans -- Education -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Lerner, Arnold; Ulysses S. Grant Scholarship Foundation
- Inventory
  - Ulysses S. Grant Scholarship Foundation
    - After-school clubs (Link Clubs), 1961-1962, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Benefit musical, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Committee to study Yale's role in the welfare of New Haven youth, 1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Description of program, general information, 1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dixwell Community Council, 1960-1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Finances, donations, 1961-1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Lerner, Arnold: correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lists of candidates/participants, 1960-1964, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)